-=伊甸园美剧 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业途径
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-
翻译: wicky starve 伊茉
校对: 王棫垚
字幕重制：珊阑
钢        锯
岭
真实故事改编
你岂不曾听过吗
Have you not heard?
永在的耶和华 创造地极的主
The Lord is the everlasting God, the Creator of the ends of the Earth.
从不疲乏 也不困倦
He will not grow tired or weary,
他的智慧无法测度
and His understanding no one can fathom.
疲乏者 他赐能力 软弱者 他加力量
He gives strength to the weary and increases the power of the weak.
即使少年 也会疲乏困倦 也会绊住跌倒
Even youths grow tired and weary, and young men stumble and fall.
但仰望上帝者 必将重新得力
But those who hope in the Lord will renew their strength.
他们必如鹰展翅上腾
They will soar on wings like eagles.
他们可奔跑而不困倦
They will run and not grow weary.
他们将行走却不疲乏
They will walk and not be faint.
戴斯蒙 挺住
Desmond, hang on!
挺住啊 戴斯蒙
Hang on, Desmond!
我们会带你离开这里的
We're going to get you out of here!
蓝脊山  弗吉尼亚州
十六年前
戴斯蒙
Desmond.
Desmond!
干什么
What?
- 等等我 - 快跟上
- Wait up. - Catch up.
等等 我有话要跟你说
Wait up, I've got something to tell you.
什么事 哈尔
What, Hal?
比赛谁先登顶吧
Race you to the top.
你耍赖
Hey! Cheater!
回头见了 小短腿
See you later,slowpoke.
- 需要拉你一把吗 - 我没事
- Want a hand? - I got it.
- 下去吧 - 蠢货
- Sit down! - Ah,you dope!
- 别闹了 - 你别闹了
- Quit it. - You quit it.
我的天啊
For Pete's sake.
快从岩脊上下来 俩倒霉孩子
Hey! Get away from that ledge,you damn fool kids!
小心摔断脖子
You're going to break your necks!
道斯家的孩子 跟他们老爸一样疯
It's them Doss kids. Crazy as their old man.
他们在杰森路和主街交口挖出一块地
They dug up the corner of Jackson and Main...
铺上了人行道
Putting in a sidewalk...
你们肯定认不出那里了
You boys wouldn't recognize it now.
估计他们也认不出你们了
Mind you,I doubt they'd recognize you.
我路过时 他们连我都不认识了
They hardly know me when I walk by 'em.
就好像我也一起死了
It's like I died with you.
就好像我们从没存在过
It's like we boys never existed.
今天就跟你们说这些了
Well,that's all I got for you today.
用右臂挡住他 戴斯蒙
Block him with your right,Desmond.
别打了 听见了吗
Stop it! Do you hear me?
- 他们怎么打起来了 - 他们打架从来不需要理由
- What are they fighting about? - When'd they ever need a reason?
汤姆 拜托
Tom! Ugh!
别拦着他们 省得我抽他们俩
Why stop 'em? Saves me whipping them both.
现在这样 我抽赢的人就行了
This way,I just whip the one that wins.
汤姆
Tom!
不要
No!
天啊
Oh,God.
汤姆
Tom!
快醒醒 能听见吗
Wake up,can you hear me?
你都干了什么
What the hell have you done?
他没反应了
He can't hear me.
我去拿些冰块
I'll get some ice.
- 把那篮子拿走 - 好的
- You shift that basket. - I got it.
他还有呼吸吗
Is he breathing?
哈尔 你能听见吗
Hal? Hal,can you hear me?
Hal,can you hear me?
哈尔 快醒醒
Hal... Come on.
他的瞳孔扩大了
He's dilated.
哈尔
Hal...
你知道自己做了什么吗
What do you think you're doin'?
我得揍你了 你知道规矩的
I'm gonna have to beat you now, you know the rules.
第六戒 不可杀人
你听见了吗 戴斯蒙
You hear me,Desmond?
第六戒 不可杀人
- 戴斯蒙 - 汤姆 别说了
- Desmond! - Tom,stop.
你揍他一顿 能让他学到什么
What's that gonna teach the boy?
他已经够暴力了
He's violent enough already.
那好吧 你继续宠着他吧
Okay,fine, you go smother him in kisses.
你来告诉他 这世界都是温柔美好的
You tell him the world's a soft and gentle place.
哈尔会没事的
Hal's gonna be okay.
- 我差点害死他 - 是啊
- I could have killed him. - Yes,you could have.
杀人是最严重的罪恶
Murder,it's the worst sin of all.
夺走别人的性命
And to take another man's life,
在上帝眼中 是最恶劣的罪行
that is the most egregious sin in the Lord's sight.
也是最让上帝难过了
Nothing hurts his heart so much.
你听不懂人话吗
Don't you understand English?
我得再跟你说一遍吗
Do I have to tell you again?
你给我让开 否则别怪我动手了
You move,woman, or I will wallop you good and hard!
大晚上吵什么 你还好吗 Bertha
What the hell's going on? You okay,Bertha?
少管闲事
You mind your own damned business!
去睡觉吧 汤姆
Go sleep it off,Tom.
我恨他
I hate him.
妈妈
Momma?
他为什么如此讨厌我们
Why does he hate us so much?
他不是讨厌我们
Oh,he don't hate us.
有时候 他是在恨自己
He hates himself sometimes.
你爸爸其实不是这样的
Your daddy tonight, that ain't the real him.
真希望你能知道 战争之前 他有多好
I wish you knew him like I did,before the war.
我们唱得怎么样 戴斯蒙
How'd we sound,Desmond?
如同天使一般 妈妈
Like a heavenly host of angels,Mom.
你知道说谎也是罪恶的 尤其在教堂里
Now,you know it's a sin to tell a lie, especially in this place.
我可没说是会唱歌的天使
Well,I ain't never said they were singing angels.
外面怎么了 戴斯蒙
What's going on out there? Desmond!
快抬起来
Get it up,get it up!
把他拖出来 拖帆布就好
Drag him out. Just the tarp.
我来叫救护车
I'll phone an ambulance.
来不及了 用Joshua的卡车
No,no time. Joshua's pickup.
- 快点 - 好的
- Quick! - Okay.
你会没事的 不会有事的
You're going to be fine now. You're going to be fine.
这里都是好医生
You're in good hands.
什么情况
What have we got here?
动脉割伤 拿缝合工具来
It's a severed artery. Get some sutures.
好的 医生
Yes,doctor.
按住这里 是你绑的止血带吗
Put some pressure on it. Did you apply this tourniquet?
- 是的 - 干得好
- Yes,sir. - Nice work.
没有你 也许他就没命了
You might have saved this boy's life.
能听见吗 你会没事的
You staying with us? You're going to be okay.
你叫什么名字 孩子
What's your name,son?
吉尔伯特
Gilbert.
- 手术吗 - 是的
- Surgery? - Yeah,surgery.
坚持住 你会没事的
Stay with us,you're gonna be okay.
感觉疼吗
You feel pain?
坚持住 好吗
Stay with us,okay?
入伍体检在那边 这里是献血室
Army physicals that way. This is for giving blood.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
这不是我的血 我没事的 谢谢关心
Oh,no,that's not mine. I'm fine. Thank you for asking though,ma'am.
你需要什么吗
What do you need?
我的腰带
My belt.
我把他借给出事故的男孩了
I lent it to the boy who had the accident.
没有腰带 我的裤子总是往下掉
My pants don't hold up so good without it.
我也没有你的腰带
Well,uh,I don't have your belt.
我知道的 腰带还在外面呢
No,I know that,ma'am. It's out there.
还在那男孩的腿上呢
It's right out there with the boy still.
好吧 我还要采血
Okay. I'm just here to take blood.
那我也要献血
I'll give mine.
好吧 你去那间屋 跟其他人一起等吧
Okay,go to that room over there and wait with the others.
我一会叫你
I'll call you.
那边的房间
That room.
你以前献过血吗 该怎么称呼你
You ever given blood before,Mr...
我姓道斯
Doss.
我的朋友都叫我戴斯蒙 我这是第一次献血
But my friends call me Desmond. No,ma'am,this is my first time.
北美珍稀鸟类
我一直梦想做医生的 但我没怎么上过学
I always dreamed about being a doctor. But,uh,I didn't get much school.
献血以后 你可能会有点晕
You may be a little dizzy when we're done.
有人来接你吗
Is somebody picking you up?
没有的 我走回去
No,ma'am. Walking back.
你住在哪呀
Where do you live?
希尔堡 女士
Fort Hill,ma'am.
那还挺远呀
That's a ways.
五六英里吧 但我会抄林间小路的
No. Just five or six miles, but I cut through the woods.
那样是七英里
It's seven that way!
看来你很喜欢树林啊
You must really like the woods.
是啊 女士 当然了
Yes,ma'am. I sure do.
好了 按住这里
Okay,put some pressure here.
- 你没事吧 - 是的
- You okay? - Yeah.
拜拜
Bye.
你要去哪呀 打扮得这么帅气
Where you going looking all spruced and nice?
我昨天认识一位医院的护士
Met someone yesterday. A nurse over at the hospital.
她叫桃乐茜·舒特 我要娶她
Her name's Dorothy Schutte. I'm gonna marry her.
天啊 她知道吗
Goodness. Does she know that?
现在还不知道 不过快知道了
Well,not yet. She's about to.
你跟女人说过话吗 除了你妈妈
You ever even spoken to a woman? I mean,one that's not family.
跟她说过
Spoke to her.
既然这样 快过来让哥抱抱
Well,in that case, come give your brother a big hug.
- 哈尔- 快过来
- Hal! - Come here.
别用你的脏手碰我
Keep your greasy paws off of me.
祝我好运 妈妈
Wish me luck,Momma.
祝你好运啦
Good luck.
下一位
Next.
坐下吧 以前献过血吗
Grab a seat. You ever given blood before?
是的 女士
Yes,ma'am. I have.
你是腰带先生
You're the belt man.
没错 我是戴斯蒙
Desmond,yes,ma'am.
戴斯蒙 不能连着两天献血
Well,Desmond,we can't take your blood two days in a row.
没事 我是来要回我的血
Well,that's good. I came to get mine back.
- 什么 - 我要把我的血拿回来
- You what? - My blood. I need it back.
献血不是这样的 我们不能还给你
Well,it don't work like that, we can't just give it back to you.
你必须还给我
Well,you got to.
自从被你扎了一针
Ever since you stuck me with that needle,
我的心脏就跳得特别快
my heart's been beating real fast.
每次想起你 心跳就更快了
Every time I think about you, it beats faster still.
第一次被这样搭讪 太老套了
I never heard that one before. It's pretty corny.
是吗
It is?
太丢人了 我练了一个晚上呢
That's a shame, I done practiced that all night.
还不够好吗
No good?
我可没这么说
I didn't say that.
动脉和静脉有什么区别
What's the difference between an artery and a vein?
- 你在说什么 - 那男孩的事故
- What are you talking about? - The boy's accident.
动脉会喷血
Arteries spurt blood.
那静脉呢
And veins?
静脉是流血
Bleed.
我觉得 你得先练练
I think you need to practice
如何跟女生聊天 再出来约会
your boy/girl dating talk at home before you come out.
是哦 确实需要
Yeah,I probably do.
如果你感兴趣 我可以送你一本书
I'll give you a book if you're that interested.
讲约会的书吗
On dating?
讲血液的书
On blood.
你还有什么医学问题吗
Another medical question perhaps?
没有 我觉得你是我见过最漂亮的人
No. I just think you're the prettiest thing I ever seen.
那是因为这里太黑了
That's because I'm sitting in the dark.
不是 你就是很美
No,you're just beautiful.
闪开
Out of the way!
开车看着点路啊
You need to watch where you're going.
对不起 我不知道你介意
I'm sorry. I didn't think you'd mind.
你都没说一声
You didn't ask.
- 我以为你会喜欢 - 那也要先说一声
- I thought you might have liked it. - Well,I might have if you'd asked.
你不过来吗
You coming?
你怎么都不跟我们说一声
Why didn't you say nothing to us?
因为你会试着阻止我的
'Cause you would have tried and talked me out of it,
- 我知道自己没做错 - 还记得主的训诫吗
- and I know what I'm doing is right. - And what about His Commandment?
我不是去杀人的 而是去自卫
It's not killing in a war. It's protecting.
教会的很多男生都去参军了
Loads of boys from our church are going.
现在是战时 国家需要男人
There is a war and they need men.
在造纸厂工作 没法保家卫国
And working in a paper mill ain't going to save this country.
我们的孩子像电影明星一样
Looks like a movie star,our boy.
军装很帅 帽子不错
Nice uniform,good hat.
让我想起去法国前 阿蒂·吉登斯穿军装的样子
Reminds me of how Artie Giddens looked in his uniform when we went to France.
- 还记得他吗 Bertha - 别说了 汤姆
- Remember him,Bertha? - Don't,Tom.
怎么了
What?
我只是想说 阿蒂穿军装潇洒极了
I'm just saying how snappy Artie looked in his uniform.
好像你们女生都这样觉得
All you girls certainly seemed to think so.
好多女生围着他 他可得瑟了
He had them flocking to him. He was most proud.
我只希望 哈尔中枪时
I just hope that when our Hal gets shot,
子弹直接从夹克正面穿透
it's through the front of his jacket.
一处射入伤 不会太血腥
Like a simple entry wound, not much mess.
阿蒂是后背中枪的
Artie got hit in the back,
子弹穿膛而过 把内脏和肠子都带出来了
it blew most of his guts and intestines out his front,offal everywhere.
军装也都烂了
Wrecked his uniform entirely.
还好他死了
It was lucky he was dead,
没有看到自己的军装被毁了
so he never knew how awful his uniform looked.
离我远点
Get outta of my sight.
你是山羊附体吗
What are you,part mountain goat?
你到底要不要帮我 戴斯蒙德·道斯
Are you going to help me,Desmond Doss,
还是把我丢在下面
or are you just going to leave me stranded?
我可以帮你 但这是有代价的
I'll help you,but it's gonna cost you.
什么代价
What?
亲我一下
A kiss.
- 这是敲诈呀 - 是的 没错
- That is pure blackmail. - Well,yes,ma'am,it is.
但这就是我的条件
But that is still my condition.
那就算成交了 我来拉你上去
That's the deal. And I'm going to hold you to it.
先等等
Well,hold on now.
这次不会扇我了吧
You ain't gonna slap me,are you?
因为如果我掉下去 会拉着你一起的
'Cause I fall off, I'm going to take you with me.
亲我试试看咯
Kiss me and find out.
怎么了
What?
我要入伍
I have to enlist.
我不能自己留下 让别人为我战斗
I can't stay here while all of them go fight for me.
- 你可以留下的 - 桃乐茜 我必须参军
- Yes,you can. You can stay here. - Dorothy,I have to.
我想做军医
I want to be a medic.
我会去救人 而不是杀人
I figure I'll be saving people, not killing them.
我要去上班了 要迟到了
I have to go to work. I'm going to be late.
桃乐茜 宝贝
Dorothy. Dorothy,darling. Dorothy. Dorothy!
所以你到底要不要求婚呀
So are you going to ask me to marry you or what?
我不知道 你还愿意跟我在一起吗
Well,I don't know. You still going to have me?
我不知道 你又没问
Well,I wouldn't know, you haven't asked.
那我要问你 发自肺腑地问你
Well,I'm asking you, with all my heart and then some.
- 你愿意嫁给我吗 - 是的 我愿意
- Will you marry me? - Then,yes. Yes,I will.
什么时候
When?
等你第一次休假回来
Soon as you get your first leave.
但是我现在还不想理你
But I still don't like you at this moment.
- 好吧 - 好的
- Yeah. - Okay.
好吧 我爱你
Okay. Well,I love you.
妈妈让我来这找你
Momma said come see you here.
是啊
Yeah.
这仨人是我最铁的哥们
These three were my best friends.
我们从小一起长大的
I grew up with 'em,
我们一起闯祸 一起追女生
I got into trouble with 'em, chased girls with 'em.
然后一起参军
And I enlisted with 'em.
现在我的朋友们都在这了
Now my friends are there,
埋在泥土之下 成为蚯蚓之食
covered in dirt and grass and eaten by worms.
我不想以后来这看我的儿子
I don't want to have to visit my sons here.
爸爸 我已经报名了
Daddy,I signed up already.
爸爸 我没法不去 别人都去了
I couldn't do otherwise,Pop. Everybody else is doing...
你又不是别人
You ain't everybody else!
别人头脑一热 都没细想 就入伍了
Everybody else jumps in and does things quick,without thinking!
就像我们当年一样傻
Like the damn idiot fools we were.
那些活下来的战士 是因为他们有能力
And soldiers who live, they live because they can do that!
你做不到的
You can't!
你总得坐下来思考 遇事要去祈祷
Look,you gotta sit and think and pray about everything.
你瞧瞧 你现在就在这样
I mean,look at you, you're doing it right now.
如果你去战场 根本活不下来的
You won't be able to live with yourself if you go.
如果我不去 我才没法活下去
No,I won't be able to live with myself if I don't.
我会做军医 我要这样为国效力
I'm going to be a medic. That's going to be my way to serve.
你又来了 感觉自己都想清楚了
See,there you go,thinking it all out.
你真以为战争能容下你 能如你所想吗
What,you figure this war is just going to fit in with you,your ideas?
我知道这肯定有难度
Well,I don't doubt it's going to be hard.
不是有难度 而是不可能
It won't be hard,it'll be impossible.
我跟你讲 不管你的脑子里有什么疯狂想法
You know,whatever beliefs you have in your crazy head now,
都不可能实现 根本不是那样的
they won't ever play out. It don't work that way.
即使你走运 奇迹般活下来
And if by some,I don't know, miracle chance you survive,
你也不会去感谢上帝的
you won't be giving no thanks to God.
- 准备好了吗 - 好了
- Ready? - Ready.
不要挤在这里
Y'all need some air.
快点 各位 动起来 国家需要你们
Come on,fellas,shake a leg. Uncle Sam's got you now.
跟妈妈道别吧 快点
Say goodbye to Momma. Come on.
女士们 不要靠近汽车了
Ladies,please,step away from the bus.
我差点忘了 给你的
I almost forgot. Here.
我希望你带着这本圣经 这是我的
I want you to have this. It's mine.
你就放在这里 把我也放这里
You keep it right here,where I'll be.
- 拜拜 - 拜拜
- Bye. - Bye.
我爱你
I love you.
抱歉 兄弟
Hey. Sorry,pal.
我每次回来 都得看你的畸形身材吗
Do I have to gaze at your deformity every time I walk to my bed?
随便看啊 随便嫉妒 老兄
Gaze upon it in envy,my friend.
你还好吗 迷路了吗 这里是空床
You okay there? You look lost. Vacancy right here.
这边风景不错 能看到山和湖
Wise choice. It's got views of the mountains down to the lake.
我叫Randall Fuller
Randall Fuller.
我叫戴斯蒙德·道斯
Desmond Doss.
叫他"教授" 没人懂他说的话
Call him "Teach." No one understands a word he says.
那是因为这里的人都不识字
That's because no one else here can read.
那暴露狂管自己叫"好莱坞"
The testicles there belong to a man calling himself "Hollywood."
块头挺大 下面挺小
They look like they belong to a smaller guy.
你还挺懂呀
You know testicles.
拜托 这是新鞋
Oh! Hey,I just got these shoes.
我叫格里瑟·诺兰 来自红钩 你是哪的人
Hey,uh,Grease Nolan,outta Red Hook. Where you from?
- 弗吉尼亚 - 乡巴佬呀
- Virginia. - Ooh,hillbilly,huh?
你娶了你表妹吗
You marry your first cousin?
我开玩笑的
I'm just joking.
那是史密提 他在教训柯辛斯基
That's Smitty over there, whipping Kirzinski's ass.
好像你比我厉害似的 白痴
Like you were doing any better,chowder head.
我不是想让你难看
Hey,I didn't want to embarrass you.
沃尔·柯辛斯基 很高兴认识你
Wal Kirzinski,nice to meet you.
竹竿 你叫什么来着
Hey,beanpole, what did you say your name was?
戴斯蒙德·道斯
Desmond Doss.
那位是特克斯·刘易斯 他觉得自己是牛仔
That's Tex Lewis over there, he thinks he's some kind of cowboy.
维托 虽然个头不高 但是非常凶
And,uh,Vito Rinnelli. He may be small,but he is a bulldog.
- 嗨 - 你好啊
- Hey. - How you doing?
- 戴斯蒙 - 你好啊
- Desmond. - Yeah.
这位帅哥叫乐琪·福特
This handsome guy right here is Lucky Ford.
那俩自以为是赌神的 是沃克和平尼克
That's Walker and Pinnick over there pretending they're card sharks.
消停一会 行吗 格里瑟
Pipe down,Grease,all right?
别耍嘴皮子 有本事拿钱过来啊
Unless you want to put your money where your mouth is.
哎哟 这书不错吧
Oh,hey,the old good book,right?
我觉得乐琪的书也不错
I think Lucky's got a good book.
- 是吧 乐琪 - 是一本好书
- Right,Lucky? - It's a good read.
全体集合
Attention!
站好队 动起来
Line up! Move it!
速度点 动起来
Let's go,move it. Move it.
你长得很奇怪啊
You are a very strange-looking individual
别介意我这样说 列兵
if you don't mind me saying so,Private.
- 你叫什么 - 安迪·沃克
- Name? - Andy Walker.
你已经死多久了 小子
How long have you been dead,son?
- 长官 - 我不是"长官"
- Sir? - I am not "Sir"!
叫我豪威尔中士 没用的人才叫长官
I am Sergeant Howell or Sarge. "Sir" you save for useless people.
- 你说自己叫"食尸鬼"吗 - 我叫沃克 中士
- The name is "Ghoul," you say? - Walker,Sergeant!
- 就叫食尸鬼了 - 好的 中士
- Ghoul it is. - Yes,Sergeant!
你看起来有点不对劲 列兵
There's something off in your presentation,Private.
说不出来哪有问题
Can't place it.
是你的头发吗
Is it your hair?
还是裤子有褶了
Is it the wrinkle in your trousers?
我脚上有一把刀 中士
I have a knife in my foot,Sergeant.
是哦 就是这里了 有一把刀
Oh,yes,of course,that's it. The knife.
- 你叫什么名字 - 史密提·莱克(
- What is your name,soldier? - Smitty Ryker.
不 你叫蠢货列兵 知道为什么吗
No,your name is Private Idiot. Do you know why?
- 因为我脚上有一把刀 - 谁插上去的 列兵
- Because I have a knife in my foot. - Who placed the knife there,Private?
中士 这是意外 我们在切磋的
It was an accident,Sarge. We was playing Stretch.
我很欣慰 竟然不是你自己插上去的
I am heartened by the knowledge you did not place it there with intention.
是谁扔的刀
Who threw the knife?
是我 中士 列兵柯辛斯基
I did,Sergeant. Private Kirzinski.
你有印第安血统吧 是哪个部落的 小子
You look part Indian. To what tribe do you belong,son?
不 我是波兰人
No,I'm Polish.
不对 你准有彻罗基族或萧尼族血统
Wrong. I believe you must have Cherokee or Shawnee blood in you.
- 没有 中士 - 你在跟我顶嘴吗
- No,Sergeant. - Are you contradicting me,
- 你这傻逼混帐东西 - 不是 中士
- you wagon-burning son of a bitch? - No,Sergeant!
让我听听印第安人的战阵呐喊 小子
Let me see your Indian war cry,son.
我不会...
I don't...
大声点 让我听听
Louder! Let me see it.
你的野兽精神呢 你是花纹蛇吗
What is your animal spirit? Are you a garter snake?
- 不 中士 - 你是花栗鼠吗
- No,Sergeant! - Are you a chipmunk?
- 不 中士 - 你是跳舞的麋鹿吗
- No,Sergeant! - Are you a dancing reindeer?
- 不 中士 - 你是在顶嘴吗 列兵
- No,Sergeant! - Are you contradicting me,Private?
- 不是 中士 - 很好
- No,Sergeant! - Good.
那从此以后 我就叫你"酋长"了
Then I shall henceforth call you "Chief"
以示对你们部族的尊重
as a sign of great respect to your people.
谢谢 中士
Thank you,Sergeant!
小子 你在笑我吗 还是你本来就很爱笑
Are you grinning at me,boy, or is that your natural state?
不 中士
No,Sergeant.
- 你叫什么 - 戴斯蒙德·道斯
- Name,Private? - Desmond Doss.
我见过比你更壮的玉米秆
I have seen stalks of corn with better physiques.
搞得我想把你的耳朵拧掉 列兵
Makes me want to pull an ear off,Private.
- 你能背动你这样重的人吗 - 是的 中士
- Can you carry your weight? - Yes,Sergeant!
你这么瘦 当然简单
Should be easy for you,then.
- 下士 - 中士
- Corporal. - Sergeant.
记得别让这小子被大风刮跑了
Make sure you keep this man away from strong winds.
是的 中士
Yes,Sergeant.
- 蠢货列兵 - 是的 中士
- Private Idiot. - Yes,Sergeant.
抬起脚来 抬高一点
Raise your foot. Higher.
所有人都出去 赶紧的 动起来
Everyone outside. Now! Move it.
我说赶紧动起来
I said move it.
好的 我先穿上军装 中士
All right. Just getting in my uniform,Sarge.
- 我让他穿了吗 下士 - 好像没有 中士
- Did I ask him to,Corporal? - No memory of it,Sarge.
我相信喜欢在屋里光着屁股的人
I believe any man who takes such pride in his natural naked state
肯定也喜欢到外面吹吹风
will surely enjoy the brisk of the outdoors.
光着老二出去吧 二等兵
Now move your privates,Private Parts!
快一点 暴露狂
Move it! You son of an exhibitionist!
下面要教你们 如何系单套结
I am going to teach you how to tie a bowline knot,
你们这些废物就能从高地下来了
so you can get your sorry asses down from a height,
我就能继续教训你们了
so I may then kick them!
绕一个圈 这是兔子洞
Create a loop. This is the rabbit hole.
兔子逃出洞 绕树跑一圈
The rabbit comes out of his hole, runs around the tree,
又回到洞里 开始吧
goes back into the hole. All right,let's go!
做得不错 特克斯
Very good,Tex.
加把劲 教授
Keep struggling,Teach.
你套过山羊吗 好莱坞
Have you ever roped a goat,Hollywood?
没有 中士
No,Sarge.
你凝视过山羊的眼睛吗
Have you ever looked into a goat's eyes?
- 没有 中士 - 很好 否则就太变态了
- No,Sarge. - Good,that would be unnatural.
你知道如果继续憋气 你会死掉吧
You know if you don't breathe, you'll die.
不错 蠢货列兵
Good,Private Idiot.
祝贺你 小胖墩 你刚从50英尺的地方摔断了脖子
Congratulations, Greaseball,you just fell 50 feet and broke your neck!
干得漂亮 列兵维托
Brilliant,Private Vito Rinnelli.
你刚把自己勒死了 白痴
You strangled yourself,numb nuts!
- 你是墨索里尼的粉丝吗 - 不是 中士
- Are you a fan of Benito? - No,Sergeant.
那就长高点 美国人都要更魁梧
A bit taller. If you were American,you'd be taller.
道斯 这是什么玩意 一边奶子一个吗
What've we got here,Doss, one for each titty?
你是在打绳结 不是编胸罩
You were tying a bowline,boy, not building a bra!
- 很好笑吗 下士 - 我不知道 中士
- What is so funny,Corporal? - Couldn't tell you,Sergeant.
快点 小姑娘似的 跑起来 快跟上
Come on! Come on,ladies, pick it up! Move it! Move it!
我要看到你们的热情 快加把劲
I want to see some fire here. A little hustle.
拿出点本事来
Show me something!
跑起来
Run like you mean it!
- 下去 快点 - 快点 跑起来
- Down,down,down! Faster,faster! - Come on. Move it! Move it!
来吧 小伙子们 洗澡时间
Let's go,it's bath time,boys! It's bath time!
快爬 快爬
Move! Move! Move!
让我看看你们的本事 快点
I want to see you work. Let's go!
快点 快点
Dig,dig,dig!
别让后面追上了 跑起来
Don't forget behind your ears. Let's go. Move!
你好像挺享受的 裸体原始人
I bet you're enjoying this, you naked degenerate.
加油 动起来
Let's go! Hustle. Hustle. Hustle. Move!
跑起来 你在等什么 跑起来
Let's go! What are we waiting on? Let's go! Move your ass!
蹬住木头 翻墙过去 别被扎到了
Get the wood! Get the wall! Don't get splinters!
冲啊
Drive!
天呐 你还好吗
Jeez,are you okay?
我没事
Yeah,I'm fine.
- 提起精神来 - 跑起来 快点
- Some spirit here,boys. Move! - Come on,move!
你脑子有病吗 让你休息了吗
What the hell is wrong with you? No one said take a rest!
快跑到终点线去 快点
Move your asses to the finish line! Move! Move!
冲刺 冲刺
Hustle! Hustle!
跑到终点去
Get your asses across that line!
时间到 干得不错 道斯
Time! Nice work,Doss!
这是美国政府给你们的礼物
This is a personal gift from the United States government
每人一把
to each and every one of you.
标准的美国步枪 7.62毫米口径 M1型
A standard issue U.S. rifle, caliber .30,M1,
自动上膛的半自动肩扛式武器
a clip-fed,shoulder-fired, semi-automatic weapon
专门设计用来杀敌的
designed to bring death and destruction to the enemy.
这将会成为你们的爱人 情人 情妇
This is to be your lover, your mistress,your concubine.
也许会成为你们此生的真爱
Perhaps the only thing in life you will ever truly love.
兄弟们 舞会开始 来挑女伴吧
Fellas,let's dance. Grab a girl.
枪口别朝前
Don't point your gun forward.
我今天可不想中枪
I do not want to be shot today.
即使你们想给我一枪
No matter how much you are tempted.
把枪立在身体侧面
Place the weapon by your side.
都注意
Pay attention.
有什么问题吗 玉米杆
Problem,Private Corn Stalk?
大小不合适 还是颜色不喜欢
Is there not one in your size, or is it the color that is the issue?
不 中士
No,Sarge.
他们跟我说 不是必须扛枪
I was... I was told I don't have to carry a weapon.
再说一遍 你走近点 我肯定是听错了
Come again? Step forward,Private. I can't be hearing this right.
很抱歉 中士
Well,I'm sorry,Sergeant.
我不能碰枪
I can't touch a gun.
到底是什么问题
What exactly is the problem?
没有问题 只是搞错了
No problem,just a mistake,sir.
我参军时 已经说明过了
I told the Army when I joined up.
那不可能
That's not possible.
你知道为什么不可能吗 列兵
Do you know why it's not possible,Private?
不知道 长官
No,sir.
因为美国军队是不会犯错的
Because the United States Army does not make mistakes.
所以如果出了问题 那就是你的问题
So if there's a problem, you must be that problem.
我只是不应该被编入步枪连队
I was just never supposed to be sent to a rifle company.
他因信仰拒服兵役 长官
He's a C.O.,sir.
你因为信仰拒服兵役 却跑来参军
You're a conscientious objector, and you joined the Army?
不是 长官 我是尽职的合作者
Well,no,sir, I'm a conscientious cooperator.
- 你在逗我吗 道斯 - 不是 长官 我是自愿参军的
- Are you screwing with me,Doss? - No. No,sir. I volunteered.
我愿意穿军装
I ain't got no problem with wearing my uniform,
致敬国旗 尽职尽责 这些都没问题
or saluting the flag and doing my duty.
我只是做不到开枪杀人
It's just carrying a gun and the taking of human life.
- 你只是不杀人吗 - 是的 长官
- You don't kill? That's all. - Yes,sir,that's all.
你知道战争会死伤众多吧
You know quite a bit of killing does occur in a war?
是的 长官
Yes,sir.
杀戮是战争的本质
I mean, that is the essential nature of war.
- 是的 长官 - 好吧
- Yes,sir. - All right.
你对美国军队还有什么要求吗
Do you have any other requirements of the United States Army?
我们还能做些什么
Is there anything else that we can do to ensure
才能让你舒服地留下来
that you have a comfortable stay here with us?
他想周六休息 长官
He doesn't want to work on Saturdays,sir.
没错 我是基督复临安息日会的
Well,Saturdays... I'm a Seventh-day Adventist.
周六是我的安息日 所以我不能干活
So,Saturday is my Sabbath, so I'm not allowed to work then.
我觉得这不是问题 你说呢 中士
I don't think that poses a problem, do you,Sergeant?
干脆告诉敌人 安息日不要进攻
We shall simply ask the enemy not to invade on the Sabbath,
因为列兵道斯要祈祷
'cause Private Doss here is at prayer.
好吧 我们都搞清楚了
All right. Now we got that clear.
现在我来说说我的要求
Now let me tell you my requirements.
其实很简单 不像你的那么复杂
They're not as complicated as yours. They're very simple.
只要你还在我们连队里 在我的手下当兵
As long as you're in this company, under my command,
就必须服从我的命令 就这样
you will obey my orders. Period.
如果你在这做不到 在战场上也没法指望你
If you can't do it here, I can't trust you to do it in battle.
我将按照第八条例 以精神问题开除你
I'm putting you in for a Section 8,psychiatric discharge.
解散
Dismissed.
先生们
Gentlemen!
大家来看看列兵戴斯蒙德·道斯
I want you to meet Private Desmond Doss.
很显然 列兵道斯并不崇尚武力
Apparently, Private Doss does not believe in violence.
他也不会使用武力
He does not practice violence.
甚至不愿意屈尊碰枪
He will not even deign to touch a weapon.
列兵道斯因为信仰拒服兵役
You see, Private Doss is a conscientious objector.
所以告诫各位 别指望他在战场上救你们
So I plead with you, do not look to him to save you on the battlefield,
因为他肯定会忙着跟良心作斗争
because he will undoubtedly be too busy wrestling with his conscience to assist.
- 中士 不是那样的 - 不许插嘴
- Sarge, that's not true. - Private, as you were.
我知道你们会有人对此有意见
Now, I realize some of you might have strong feelings about this.
但我们正是因此而战
It is what we men fight for.
去维护我们的权利 保护女人和孩子
To defend our rights, and to protect our women and children.
即使列兵道斯的信仰 会夺走女人和孩子的生命
Even if Private Doss' beliefs might cause women and children to die.
所以我希望连里的每一个人
So I will expect everyone in this company
都能给列兵道斯足够的尊重
to give Private Doss the full measure of respect he is due
反正他很快就要走了
for the short time he will be with us.
我说清楚了吗
Am I clear?
是的 中士
Yes, Sergeant.
你拿的什么 Dessie
What'cha got there, Dessie?
你知道那是什么
You know what that is.
这本有点小呢
It just seems kind of small.
小本圣经 给小男人看
It's half the Bible for half the man.
史密提 看在上帝份上 把圣经还给他吧
For Pete's sake, Smitty, give him back his Bible.
我又没跟你说话
I don't remember speaking to you.
为什么你不打架 觉得比我们高尚吗
So, how come you don't fight? You think you're better than us?
不
No.
如果有人打你呢
What if you was attacked?
就像这样
Say, like that.
圣经让你把另一边脸也转过来吗
The Bible says to turn the other cheek, don't it?
所以我觉得这不是信仰问题
See, I don't think this is a question of religion, fellas.
我觉得你就是懦夫 就这么简单
I think this is cowardice, plain and simple.
道斯 对吗 你是胆小鬼吧
Is that right, Doss? Are you chickenshit, that it?
来啊 打我
Go on, take a poke.
这样吧 我让你两只手
Tell you what, I'm going to give you a free shot.
像这样
Right there.
打我啊 来打我 道斯
Hit me, Doss. Go on.
- 快去打他 - 快上啊
- Let him have it. - Go ahead.
不来吗
No?
胆小鬼
Chickenshit.
这是啥啊
Hold on here. What is this?
还给我
Give me that.
- 妹子长得不错呀 - 可以啊
- This is a fine-looking broad. - Nice.
传来给我们看看
Hey, pass it around.
这样的美妞 就该配一个真正的男人
Now, this would be the kind of broad that deserves a real man.
快还给我
Give me that back.
求我
Please.
求你了
"求你还给我 史密提"
"Please give it back, Smitty."
求你还给我 史密提
Please give it back, Smitty.
你有幻听吗 戴斯蒙
Do you hear voices, Desmond?
没有 长官
No, sir.
根据我的理解 上帝会跟你说话 是吗
But I understand that God talks to you. Is that right?
长官 我不是疯子
Sir, I'm not a crazy person.
你是不是觉得 所有人都把你当成疯子
Is that how you feel most people regard you, a crazy person?
我知道自己有点不同 但是...
I'm different. I know that, but...
我不会装出另一副模样
I'm not going to pretend to be something I'm not.
- 我就是我 - 听起来挺孤独的
- I am what I am. - Sounds lonely.
你孤独吗
You lonely?
- 所以你没有幻听 - 没有 长官
- So, you don't hear voices. - No, sir.
我向上帝祈祷 希望他能听见 但那不是对话
I pray to God and I like to think He hears me, but it ain't a conversation,
不像我们现在假装在做的
like the one we're pretending to have right now.
- 假装吗 - 是的 长官
- Pretending, Private? - Well, yes, sir.
我知道你是想按第八条例 把我从部队开除
I know all you really want to do is give me a Section 8,drum me out of the Army,
但我的脑子没问题 只是在坚持信仰
but I'm not off up above. I just simply believe what I believe.
我是在试着理解你 好吗
Well, I'm trying to understand, all right?
是上帝告诉你 不要碰枪的吗
Was it God who told you not to pick up a rifle?
上帝说 不要杀戮
God says not to kill.
那是最重要的诫命之一
That's one of His most important Commandments.
大部分人会理解成 不能谋杀
Most people take that to mean, "Don't commit murder."
而战争完全是另一码事
War is a completely different set of circumstances.
耶稣说过 我给你们一条新诫命
Jesus said, "A new Commandment I give unto you,
是让你们彼此相爱 如同我爱你们
that you love one another, just as I have loved you."
我们要对抗的 那可是撒旦
This is Satan himself we're fighting.
作为基督徒 你应该明白的
Surely, as a good Christian, you can see that.
我知道的 所以我才来参军
I can see that, sir, and that is why I joined up.
但很抱歉 我不会碰武器的
But I'm sorry, I will not bear arms.
他的宗教观很独特
His religious views are certainly unique,
但还不满足第八条例的驱逐条件
but they do not constitute grounds for a Section 8 discharge.
有这样的人在 我怎么维持纪律
How am I supposed to maintain discipline with a man like that in my unit?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他是出于信仰拒服兵役
But he is a legitimate conscientious objector,
必须允许他做医务兵
and he must be allowed to work as a combat medic,
只要他能通过其他所有科目的训练
provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training.
也许我们可以权当认同他的想法
Perhaps we could help make believe in his idea.
是啊 把他扔到营房和炊事班吧
Yeah, you restrict him to barracks and KP.
再跟你扯上帝 就让他尝尝地狱的滋味
If he throws God at you, you throw hell right at him.
我要让他滚
I want him gone.
道斯 你这里太乱了 简直是猪圈
Doss, your area is a disgrace. It's a pig sty!
- 好笑吗 莱克 - 不 中士
- Something funny, Ryker? - No, Sarge!
- 你的脑子里有屎吗 - 不 中士
- You got some shit on your mind? - No, Sarge!
你们都没有认识到
What you men fail to recognize
连队的水平是由最弱的人决定的
is a unit is no better than its weakest member!
得让你们长点脑子 这周末都不准请假
Now, to help you learn that lesson, there will be no passes this weekend.
都去炊事班帮厨
You will all be on KP!
现在所有人都去20英里全装越野
Right now, everybody in full gear for a 20-mile hike.
出发
Let's go! Let's go.
把头抬起来
Get your heads right.
不要一副可怜相
Don't start feeling sorry for yourself.
可怜兮兮的样子 让我看着恶心
Makes me sick see you feel sorry for yourself.
你们根本不知道什么叫累
You dogs don't know what tired is.
我不倒下 谁也不准停
We're going to keep going till I drop.
别打了 我还要睡觉呢
Hey, knock it off. Trying to sleep here.
- 别碰我 - 好吧
- Get off me. Get off me. - Okay. All right.
你怎么还在这
Why the hell are you still here?
原地不用动
As you were.
道斯去哪了
Where's Doss?
这样对谁都没好处
This isn't good for anybody.
这也不是我参军的目的
Sure ain't what I joined up for.
这跟你为什么参军没关系
It's not about what you joined up for.
这关乎这里所有人的性命
It's about the lives of every man in here.
也包括你的性命 你该退出了
And yours, son. It's time to quit this.
穿好衣服 我送你出去
Finish getting dressed and I'll walk you down.
没关系的 道斯
It's okay, Doss.
这一点也不丢人
There's no shame in this.
走吧
Let's go.
我今天要站岗 早晨还要去帮厨 所以...
I got extra guard duty today, and I'm on KP this morning, so...
我不能走
Can't.
好吧 道斯
All right, Doss.
列兵道斯 你能认出打你的人吗
Private Doss, can you identify the men that beat you?
不能 中士
No, Sarge.
所以你不知道谁揍了你吗
Are you saying that you don't know who attacked you?
我从没说过 我被人揍过 中士
I never said I was attacked, Sarge.
你到底在说什么 道斯
Well, what the hell are you saying, Doss?
你睡觉搞出半身淤青吗
You bruised half your body sleeping?
我睡觉不老实
I... I sleep pretty hard.
好吧
Alright.
周末要湿身的人 记得带安全套
If you plan on getting wet this weekend, make sure you put on a hat.
下一个
Next.
不要带着一身奶味回来
Don't want anyone coming back pissing cream.
你的咖啡里不加点奶吗 中士
What, you don't want none for your coffee, Sarge?
要不现在来一发 史密提
How about a shot right now, Smitty?
这是你的经验之谈吗 中士
You speaking from experience, Sarge?
那你得回去问问你妈了 小胖墩
You'd have to ask your mom about that, Greaseball.
稍息
At ease.
列兵道斯 很抱歉 我不能准你的假
Private Doss, I'm afraid I can't authorize your pass.
通过基础训练的人 才可以享受休假
This is a furlough for men who have passed the basic training.
长官 无意冒犯 我都通过了
Well, sir, respectfully, sir, I have.
三周之前 我就申请休假了
I put in for this furlough three weeks ago.
我今天下午要结婚
I'm getting married this afternoon.
这里写着 你没通过步枪考核
It says you're not rifle qualified.
长官 我可以不持枪的 施特尔策上校说...
Well, I'm not required to carry a rifle, sir. Colonel Stelzer, he...
施特尔策上校说的是...
Colonel Stelzer's determination was...
必须允许道斯做医务兵
"Doss must be allowed to work as a combat medic,
只要他能通过其他所有科目的训练
provided he qualifies in all other areas of his training."
但你还没通过步枪考核
And you have not qualified on the rifle range, Private.
显而易见
Pretty clear.
让我看看 你知道如何持枪 我就准你的假
Show me you know how to handle a rifle and I'll sign your furlough.
- 坎农下士 - 到
- Corporal Cannon. - Sir!
把你的步枪给列兵道斯
Hand Private Doss your firearm.
- 我不会碰枪的 长官 - 我不是在跟你商量呢
- I won't touch a rifle, sir. - I'm not asking you, Private!
这是连队指挥官的命令
That is a direct order from a company commander.
道斯 别胡闹了 你退出吧
For God's sake, Doss, you stop this nonsense and quit.
拒绝的话 我只能把你送上军事法庭了
Refuse, and I will have no recourse but to court-martial you,
战争期间 你只能在军事监狱里蹲着了
and you will spend the duration of the war in a military prison.
长官 我做不到
I can't, sir.
你还想等多长时间 桃乐茜
How much longer would you like to wait, Dorothy?
我想已经足够久了
I think it's been long enough.
我很抱歉
I'm so very sorry.
有时候 男人就是会退缩的
Sometimes men just get cold feet.
有些男人会 但我的戴斯蒙不会
Some men might. Not my Desmond.
你可能会觉得 我是大混蛋
You probably think I'm a real son of a bitch
只在乎规章 不关心下属
who cares only about regulations and not his men.
能让我看看吗
May I?
我也相信这本书 像其他人一样
I believe in this book as much as any man.
像其他人一样 我的良心也会纠结
And just like any man, I wrestle with my conscience,
但当你珍视的一切遭受摧残时 你怎么办
but what do you do when everything you value in this world is under attack?
我不知道 长官
I don't know, sir.
如此深刻的问题 我没法回答
I ain't got answers to questions that big,
但我感觉 我的价值观也在遭受摧残
but I also feel like my values are under attack,
我不知道为什么
and I don't know why.
我不管你有什么原则 因为日本人不会在乎
I don't give a rat's ass about your principles because the Japs don't.
如果日本人攻击你和受伤的战友
If one of them attacks you and some wounded soldier,
你会怎么办
what are you gonna do?
用你的圣经去打他吗
Hit him with your Bible?
我准备好为战友们牺牲了
I'm prepared to give my life for my men.
光靠牺牲 是没法打赢战争的
You don't win wars by giving up your life.
听着 我来这里 只因为我不想看你烂在监狱里
Look, I'm only here because I don't want to see you rotting in a prison cell.
认罪吧 请求法庭宽恕
Plead guilty, throw yourself at the mercy of the court.
也许他们能让你回家祈祷
Maybe they'll let you go home and pray.
让那些勇士去赢得这场战争吧
Let the brave men out there go and win this war.
如果我没法说服你 也许她可以
If I can't convince you, maybe she can.
他们不让我给你打电话
They wouldn't let me call you.
我就知道 这不是你的错
I knew it wasn't your making.
他们对你做了什么
What have they done to you?
没关系 我没事的
It's okay, I'm all right.
只是对墙打了几拳 但拳头没墙硬
I just went a couple of rounds with the wall and lost.
他们说 你可能会进监狱的 Desmond
They're saying you could go to prison, Desmond.
去军事监狱
Leavenworth.
肯定还有其他办法的
There must be some other way.
我不知道还有什么办法
I don't know what that could be.
他们要求的 我都做到了 除了那件事
I've done everything they asked me, except this one thing,
因为我不想杀人 就被当成罪犯了
and I'm being treated like a criminal just 'cause I won't kill.
你努力过了 没人能反驳这一点
You tried. Nobody can say you didn't.
但在监狱里 你能救谁呢
But who are you going to save in prison?
也许谁都救不了
Probably nobody.
那为什么不能拿起破枪 装装样子呢
Then why can't you just pick up the stupid gun and wave it around?
你不用开枪 这样也算折中了
You don't have to use it, just meet them halfway.
- 我做不到 - 你可以的 只是面子问题
- I can't do that. - Yes, you can. It's just pride.
不要骄傲固执 不要误解上帝的意愿
Pride and stubbornness. Don't confuse your will with the Lord's.
我骄傲吗
Have I been prideful?
或许是吧
Maybe I am prideful.
但这样的话 我无法继续活下去
But I don't know how I'm going to live with myself
我必须忠于我的信仰
if I don't stay true to what I believe.
更不用说 如何与你共度余生
Much less how you could live with me.
你眼中的我 将达不到我的自我预期
I'd never be the man that I want to be in your eyes.
我会爱上你 是因为你与众不同
I fell in love with you because you weren't like anyone else
你也不会随波逐流
and you didn't try to be.
永远不要认为 你会让我失望
Do not think for one moment that you will disappoint me.
无论如何 我都会爱你
I will love you no matter what.
我不知道他要怎么办 他肯定赢不了
I don't know what he's gonna do. He loses no matter what.
他们想让他认罪
They want him to plead guilty,
这样一来 他会被开除军籍
but then he'll get a dishonorable discharge.
但如果反抗 他肯定会被判刑
Otherwise he fights them, and he for sure goes to prison.
不管怎样 他都会被看作懦夫
Either way,they'll call him a coward
他肯定没法忍受这些
and I don't see how he can live with that.
桃乐茜 谢谢
Well,thank you,Dorothy.
如果你有机会跟他说话
If you get to talk to him,
请告诉他 我们爱他 正在为他祈祷
tell him that we love him and that we're praying for him.
我们为你们俩祈祷
We're praying for both of you.
我会的 再见
I will. Bye-bye.
汤姆 你简直疯了 你在发神经
Tom,you're out of your mind, you're delirious.
是啊 我是疯了
Of course,I'm out of my mind.
你觉得呢 我就是疯子
What do you think I am? I'm out of my mind.
你滚出去
You leave this room.
汤姆 不要 放下枪
No,Tom! Put it down!
你滚开 臭娘们
Get away from me,woman!
先生 我来关门吧
I got that,sir.
您好 需要帮忙吗
May I help you,sir?
我想找马斯格罗夫准将谈谈
I wish to speak to Brigadier General Musgrove.
没有提前预约 那是不可能的
Not without an appointment you can't. That would be quite impossible.
能烦请您捎句话吗
Uh,if you would kindly tell him
就说托马斯·道斯下士想跟他说几句话
Corporal Thomas Doss would appreciate a brief word.
他正在开一场非常重要的会议
He's in a very important meeting.
我们曾在法国贝洛森林并肩作战 他是我的老队长
I fought with him in France at Belleau Wood. He was my captain.
麻烦您了 事关重大
Please,ma'am,it's most vital.
谢谢您
Thank you,ma'am.
外面有一位叫托马斯·道斯的人
There's a man out there,Tom Doss.
道斯吗
Doss?
很快就能结束了
Be over in a minute.
你就能毫发无损地回家了 就像什么都没发生
You'll be home safe and sound, like nothing ever happened.
我爱你
I love you.
现在是列兵戴斯蒙德·道斯一案的听证会
This is a hearing into the matter of Private Desmond Doss.
他被指控屡次违背直接命令
The charge is disobeying a series of direct orders
无视指挥官
from his commanding officer.
被告的意见如何
How says the defendant?
列兵道斯希望提出无罪抗辩
Private Doss wishes to enter a "not guilty" plea.
列兵 是这样吗 我以为已经说好了
Is that so,Private? I thought this was agreed.
你已经想要接受认罪了
You wanted to enter some sort of plea bargain.
- 是的 长官 我改主意了 - 就这样变卦吗
- Yes,sir,but I changed my mind. - Just like that?
你想进行军事审判吗
You wish to proceed to a court-martial?
是的 长官
Yes,sir.
列兵 那如你所愿 进行审判吧
Well,on your head,then,Private. Proceed.
法官大人 道斯向我们炫耀他的道德观念
Your Honor,Private Doss waves his morality at us
好像那是荣誉勋章一般
like it's some kind of badge of honor.
他不屑一顾 屡次违背直接命令
He flaunts his contempt by directly disobeying a series of direct orders
无视指挥官
from his commanding officer.
与此同时 英勇的战士们却在浴血奋战
When the very best of our young men are sacrificing their lives against...
- 你还好吗 - 还好
- You okay? - Yes.
还在审吗
Are they still deliberating?
是的
Yes,sir.
你把这封信带进去
Okay,now you go take this in there.
我不行 只有军人才能进去
I can't. It's strictly military personnel.
那你让他们带进去
Well,then you get one of them to take it in.
他们不会帮忙的 他们都想置他于死地
They ain't out to help. They're fixing to bury him.
在军事法庭上 被告只需回答一个问题
There is only one question that any military court need ask of the accused.
你是否否认 违背过萨斯顿上校的命令呢
Do you deny disobeying Colonel Sangston's direct orders?
列兵 是不是呢
Well,do you,Private?
- 我不否认 - 那你要抗辩什么呢
- No,sir. I don't. - Why are you contesting it,then?
既然你不想碰枪 那还有什么意义呢
Why is it so important to you,given your refusal to even touch a weapon,
为什么还要在战斗部队服役呢
to serve in a combat unit?
因为日本偷袭珍珠港时 我能感同身受
Because when the Japanese attacked Pearl Harbor,I took it personal.
我认识的每个人 都想奔赴战场 我也不例外
Everyone I knew was on fire to join up,including me.
在我家乡 有两个人体检不合格
There were two men in my home town... declared 4-F unfit.
因为不能参军 他们自杀了
They killed themselves because they couldn't serve.
我曾在一家国防工厂工作 可以延迟服役
I had a job in a defense plant and I could've taken a deferment,
但那是不对的
but that ain't right.
只让同胞去浴血奋战 那是不对的
It isn't right that other men should fight and die,
我不能坐享安宁
that I would just be sitting at home safe.
我需要参军
I need to serve.
我有精力和热情 去做一名军医
I got the energy and the passion to serve as a medic.
跟其他战士一同奋战 不避危险 只是...
Right in the middle with the other guys. No less danger,just...
在大家夺取生命时 我要拯救生命
While everybody else is taking life, I'm going to be saving it.
世界正在土崩瓦解
With the world so set on tearing itself apart,
我这样的选择也不错
it doesn't seem like such a bad thing to me
我想尽一己之力 挽回这个世界
to want to put a little bit of it back together.
对不起 任何人不准进入...
Sorry,sir,nobody's allowed to go...
你不懂 我的儿子是被告
No,you don't understand. My son is the defendant.
我知道 但任何人都不准许进入
I understand,sir, but nobody's allowed...
- 我有重要信息 - 您不能进去...
- I have information that's important. - Sir,you are not allowed...
虽然你的想法值得赞赏
While the sentiments expressed are laudable,
但指控显然是成立的 所以...
the facts of the charge seem incontestable,so...
外面怎么回事
What the hell is going on out there?
让他进来
Let him go.
- 这是一战的军装 - 是的
- That's a Great War uniform. - It is,sir.
我需要给您这封信
Sir,I need to show you this.
恕我直言 您已经不是军人了
With respect,sir,you are no longer a member of the military.
您不能参加本次听证会 很抱歉
You are unable to attend this hearing. I'm sorry.
真是这样吗
Is that truly the way it works,sir?
你为国家而战 失去了最珍贵的东西
You fight for your country, you lose so much that was dear to you,
然后就算完了吗
and then you're done with?
旧军装被遗忘 就无权发言了
The uniform is forgotten. You have no voice.
您参加过佛兰德斯第四战役吗
You were at Lys?
是的 还参加过贝洛森林之战
I was,sir. And at Belleau Wood.
我看到 您两次被授勋
Twice decorated,I see.
是的 长官
Yes,sir.
想必您是这位列兵的父亲
I take it you are the Private's father.
是的 我叫托马斯·道斯
I am,sir. Thomas Doss.
作为一名老兵 你也知道有法律...
Then,as a former military man, you know there are laws here...
我知道法律 也知道我的儿子会受法律保护
Sir,I know the law and I know my son is protected by those laws.
法律都是以宪法为基础的
They are framed in our constitution.
我相信法律 跟他一样的
And I believe in them,as he does.
因此我会去参战捍卫这些法律
They are why I went and fought to protect them.
至少我当时是这样认为的
At least,that is what I thought I was doing.
因为如果不是这样的话
Because if it wasn't for that,
那我都不知道 自己当时为何而战
then I have no idea what the hell I was doing there,sir.
道斯下士 谢谢
Thank you,Corporal Doss.
请把信给我吧
Let me have the letter.
您必须离开了
You must go.
被告是出于信仰拒服兵役者
The defendant's rights as a conscientious objector
其权力受到国会法案保护
are protected by an Act of Congress
不能被强制放弃那些权力
and he cannot be compelled to waive those rights.
包括本案中拒绝持枪的权力
That includes,in this case, his disobeying orders to bear arms.
落款 战争服务指挥官马斯格罗夫准将 于华盛顿特区
Signed,Brigadier General Musgrove, War Services Commander,Washington,D.C.
上校
Colonel?
- 我撤回指控 - 那就可以结案了
- I withdraw the charges,sir. - Then this case is dismissed.
道斯 你可以走上充满硝烟的战场
Private Doss,you are free to run into the hellfire of battle
可以不持枪保卫自己
without a single weapon to protect yourself.
你可以继续履行职责 受训成为一名战地医务兵
You may resume your duties and begin training as a combat medic.
- 他在哪 - 直接就走了
- Where is he? - Gone. Straight after.
我让他留下来 说你肯定想见他
I begged him to stay. I told him you'd want to see him.
没事 我明白
No,I understand.
你回家后 告诉他 我爱他
When you get home, you tell him I love him.
好的
Okay. Okay.
你一定要回来
You better come home to me.
1945年5月 冲绳
好莱坞 闭嘴吧
Hollywood,shut up.
别唱了 闭嘴
Come on,pipe down.
- 闭嘴 - 别唱了
- Shut up,man. - Shut up!
好莱坞 我发誓 我要崩了你
I swear to God, Hollywood,I will shoot you.
往嘴里塞只袜子吧 到战场再嚎吧
Put a sock in it,will you? Save the crowing for when we get there.
真扫兴
Killjoy was here.
让开
Give him room.
注意 靠边站
Clear! Clear! Move aside!
这是96步兵师 只剩这些人了
The 96th... or what's left of them.
我们就是要接替他们
These are the guys we're replacing.
- 我这里安全 - 没人
- Seems good to me. - Clear.
- 都没人 - 安全
- As gold. - Clear.
中士 这里安全
All clear,Sarge!
我是格洛弗上尉
Captain Glover.
第96步兵师 Manville中尉
Lieutenant Manville,96th.
我们被分派给您了 长官
We've been assigned to you,sir.
好的
Okay.
- 给他们点吃的 - 是的 长官
- Let's get these men some chow. - Yes,sir.
这是豪威尔中士
This is,uh,Sergeant Howell.
- 很高兴见到您 - 坐下吧
- Good to meet you,sir. - Sit down.
哪位是道斯呢
Who's Doss?
那边
Over there.
你是道斯吗
You Doss?
我是欧文·谢克特
Irv Schecter.
咱俩和佩奇是这里仅剩的医务兵了
You,and me and Page here are about the only medics we got left in this area.
我们可能要一起作战了
So,I guess we're gonna be working together.
你刚从前线下来吗
You just come off the line?
那边怎么样
What's it like?
我在问你 前线什么样
I said,What's it like?
钢锯岭
Hacksaw.
我们攀登过六次 六次都被打下来了
We climbed up six times. Six times,they threw us off.
最后一次时 96步兵师基本全军覆没
Last time,there wasn't anything left of the 96th.
他们是禽兽
They're animals.
该死的禽兽
Stinking animals.
日本人不顾自己的死活
Nips don't care if they live or die.
他们想死 不断向我们涌来
They want to die. They keep coming at you.
而且他们不会放弃
And they ain't never going to give up.
永远不会
Never.
哥们 给你
Here. Hey,buddy.
日本人专打伤员
The Japs deliberately target the wounded.
摘掉所有红十字标志吧
Lose all your Red Cross markings.
他们打死医务兵会有奖励
Nips put a premium on shooting medics.
白色袖标就是活靶子
The white is a bull's-eye.
给你一顶新头盔
Here,I got you a new helmet.
均码的
One size fits all.
这是我们的目标 钢锯岭
That's our objective. Hacksaw Ridge.
攻下这里 也许就能攻下冲绳
We take it,maybe we get Okinawa.
攻下冲绳 就能攻下日本
We get Okinawa,we take Japan.
稍等一会 让海军先给他们一点颜色看看
Take a breather. Our pals in the Navy are going to soften them up for us.
这样狂轰乱炸 没人能活下来
Nobody can survive that shit.
但是他们可以
Oh,but they can.
中尉 这仨碉堡的位置准确吗
Lieutenant,these bunkers here, here and here,is that accurate?
是的 有三个...
Yeah,there's three...
是的 可能稍微靠后 但这是全部了
Yes,sir,maybe a little further back, but it's all...
上面完全不同
It's all different up there.
可以了 上尉
All clear,Captain.
兄弟们 出发了
Gents,move out.
是血
It's blood.
别废话
No shit.
我们不是在堪萨斯了
We're not in Kansas anymore,Dorothy.
继续爬吧
Keep climbing.
来吧 我拉你
Here,come on.
让我们过去 让一下
Coming through,make way. Out of the way.
- 布朗 - 怎么
- Brown. - What?
给杰索普
Give this to Jessop.
下士
Corporal!
有敌人
Incoming!
卧倒
Get down!
趴下
他们在哪 什么都看不到
Where the hell are they? I can't see nothing.
- 我也不知道 - 他们在哪...
- Beats me,pal. - Where the...
医务兵
Medic!
我们在这边
We're over here!
杰克 把手按在这里
Put your hand right here. Put your hand on there,Jack.
没事的
Come on,come on.
没事 我们给你找掩护 跟我过来
Come on,we're going to get you under cover. Come on,come with me.
杰克 跟我过来
Come with me,Jack.
继续前进 前进
Keep moving forward! Move!
我什么都看不见
I can't see anything.
- 那是吗 - 我不知道 反正开枪吧
- Is that one? - I don't know. Just shoot!
好了 走吧
All right,let's go.
维托
Vito!
该死
Oh,shit.
- 医务兵 维托受伤了 - 我来了
- Medic! Vito's down! - I'm coming!
好了 我来了
Okay. I'm here.
闪开
Get out of the way!
你受伤了吗
You hurt?
我没事
I'm fine.
拉尔夫 我来了 深呼吸
Come on,I got you,Ralph. Just breathe.
拉尔夫 深呼吸 没事了
Just breathe. Just breathe,Ralph. It's okay. It's okay.
拉尔夫 调整呼吸
Just breathe,Ralph,just breathe.
我在呢 没事了
I got you,I got you. I got you. Come on.
打一针吗啡 继续救人
Hey! Hey! Give him a shot of morphine and move on.
他活不过今天了
He's not going to last a day.
道斯 求你了 别走啊
Please. Please,Doss,no. No. Don't leave me.
求你了 别放弃我
Don't leave me. God,please don't leave me.
我家里还有孩子
I've got kids!
求你了 救救我
Please. Please,don't. Please,don't leave me.
我哪也不去 我会带你回家的
I ain't going anywhere. I'm going to get you home.
拉尔夫 我不会走的 我会带你回家第
I got you,Ralph. Okay? I'm going to get you home.
给你打一针吗啡
Here comes the morphine. Here comes the morphine.
拉尔夫 你马上就不疼了
It's going to kick in real quick,Ralph.
马上就把你转移下去
We're going to get you shifted.
担架
Stretcher! Stretcher!
- 站起来 前进 - 不行 我受伤了
- Get up. Keep moving,son. - I can't,I'm wounded.
你什么事都没有
There's nothing wrong with you.
该死 坚持住
Shit! Hang on,kid.
快走 不动就是等死
Move. A sitting duck's a dead one.
快走
Move. Go,go,go!
他需要优先救治
This guy's a priority.
交给我们吧 放这吧
We got him,we got him. Here.
优先救治吗 没学过分诊吗 他撑不到送下去的
A priority? You ever heard of triage? He'll be dead before we get him down.
你怎么知道
You don't know that!
送他下去 好吗
Get him down. All right? Huh?
- 好的 走吧 - 好的
- Okay. Okay. Go. - Okay. Okay.
没事了 马上送你回家
It's all right,buddy. We're going to get you home.
医务兵 救命啊
Medic! Help! Help.
如果我们看不见他们 他们也看不见我们
I figure if we can't see them, then they can't see us neither.
弗兰克 我来了 你哪受伤了
I got you,Frank. Where you hit?
- 傻子 好像他们看得见 - 道斯 快走
- I think they can see us,smart ass! - Doss,come on,come on.
帮我一把
Give me a hand here.
蹲下 长官
Get down,sir.
碉堡就在那里
Over there! The bunkers.
我看见了 最好卧倒
I see them. Better stay down,sir.
- 我看见了 在正前方 - 我也看见了
- I got 'em,dead ahead. - Yeah,I see 'em,too.
尽量逼近 全火力压制
Push in as close as you can. Give them everything you've got.
我派炸药组 包抄他们
I'll send in the weapons team to flank them.
坚持住 你会没事的 好吗
You keep that tight,you're going to be right as rain. All right?
道斯 交给我吧
I got him,Doss. I got him.
你还好吗
You doing okay?
挺好
Okay.
准备 发射
And,fire!
趴下
Down!
该死的
Son of a bitch.
- 你过去 - 好的
- You,get on it. - Yes,sir!
快点 开枪
Take 'em. Go. Fire!
掩护
Cover!
食尸鬼 冲上去 躲到弹坑里
Go,go. Go,Ghoul. Get in the hole. Stay there.
史密提 快去 我们掩护 大步跨过去
Go! Go,Smitty, we'll cover you. Leapfrog.
掩护
Cover.
炸药包
Satchel!
- 食尸鬼 - 安全
- Ghoul! - Clear.
食尸鬼 坚持住
Come on,stick it. Stick it,Ghoul.
掩护
Cover! Cover!
该死
Son of a bitch.
掩护
Cover his ass.
医务兵 救命
Medic! Medic! Help me.
冲啊
Go!
医务兵
Medic!
我来了 把手按在这里
I'm here. Put your hand on it. Put your hand on it!
快冲
Go,go,go!
食尸鬼
Ghoul. Ghoul.
没事了 你哪受伤了
You're okay. Where you hit?
你的脑袋磕了一下 没事的
You got a bump on the head,that's okay.
你叫什么
What's your name?
- 安迪 - 全名是什么
- Andy. - Andy what?
安迪·沃克
Andy Walker.
外号是什么
Also known as?
食尸鬼
Ghoul.
食尸鬼 你没事的
Ghoul. Ghoul,you're okay,you're okay.
干得好 兄弟们
Good job,men. Good work.
挖好战壕过夜 守住这里
Dig in for the night. We hold this spot,
明天就能拿下整个钢锯岭
we mop up the rest of the ridge tomorrow.
孩子们 在碉堡里面或附近 给自己选好位置
Okay,boys. Find yourself a nice safe hole in or near the bunker.
每两小时换班守夜
Rotate watch every two hours.
不知道外面有什么情况 脑袋和屁股都放低
We don't know what's out there. Heads down,asses lower.
不说英语的 一律格杀勿论
And shoot anything that don't speak English.
- 也包括格里瑟吗 中士 - 尤其是他
- Does that include Grease,Sarge? - Particularly him.
不管你是要去方便 还是什么的
I don't care if you need to take a piss or a dump,
一个人出去都很危险
it ain't safe to go out there alone.
你还要去哪 道斯
Where the hell are you going,Doss?
外面还有很多伤员 中士
Still more wounded out there,Sarge.
我跟他一起去
I'll go with him.
要眼观六路 耳听八方
Be smart. Keep your ears down.
好了 各自找地方吧
All right,let's find a spot.
Rinnelli和Henry在前15分钟就直接死了
Rinnelli and Henry dead in the first 15 minutes,just straight off.
直接就死了
Straight off.
还有大眼睛彼得森 以及斯坦福和墨菲
Peterson,Popeye. Standford and Murphy.
佩奇和昂格尔
Page and Unger.
罗尔斯顿
Ralston.
和平年代 黑发人送白发人
"In peace,sons bury their fathers,"
战争年代 白发人送黑发人
"in war,fathers bury their sons."
别再唠叨那些废话了
You wanna stop spouting that crap,huh?
说那些有什么用呢
It don't help none.
是啊 没错 在这确实没用
Yeah,you got that right. Not here.
给我吧
give me that.
这名伤员腹部受伤了
Hey,we've got an abdominal wound.
他需要输一点血
This man is going to need some plasma.
- 没问题 - 交给我们吧
- You got it. - Leave him with us.
好了 你没事了 他们会救你的
Okay. You're okay now. They got you.
我们要找一个洞来栖身
Should we find a hole and dig in?
好主意
Sounds good to me.
戴上头盔
Put your helmet on.
你不吃吗
You ain't going to eat them?
我不吃肉 你吃吧
I don't eat meat. Help yourself.
你当然不吃肉了
Of course you don't.
她真挺漂亮的
That's one heck of a dame.
你这样的 通常很难追到她 你知道吧
You know you're fighting out of your weight class with her,don't you?
是啊 我知道
Yes,I do.
别告诉她
Don't tell her that.
跟我这样的男人在一起 她会更幸福
She'd be much happier with a man like me anyway.
是啊 直到她了解你
Yeah,until she got to know you.
我偶尔挺混蛋的
I'm an asshole sometimes.
只是偶尔吗
Sometimes?
行吧 有你的
Yeah,all right. All right.
这些日本人太狡猾了
These Japs are sneaky.
我先去放哨吧 你休息一会
I'll take first watch,all right? You get some shut-eye.
做恶梦啦
Hell of a dream.
梦到我被刺穿了 但什么都做不了
Dreamed I got myself skewered. I couldn't do nothing.
步枪就在这
Rifle's just there.
枪不会咬人的
It won't bite.
它会的
Yeah,it will.
看看你周围
Look around you.
经历过今天的场面
After what we've just been through,
任何正常的人都会想找武器的
any sane man would be screaming for a weapon.
我没说过我是正常的
I never claimed to be sane.
我爸是酒鬼
My daddy's a drunk.
他早就想戒酒 但是一直戒不掉
He fought it for years, but it kind of got a hold of him hard.
这让他变得很刻薄
Made him mean.
至少你知道你爸是谁
Least you knew him.
我都不知道我爸是谁 我也懒得知道
Mine could have been any one of 10 guys, and none of them worth a damn,so...
所以你是妈妈养大的
So,your momma raised you?
我认识她 但我五岁时 就被她扔进孤儿院了
I knew her,but she gave me to an orphanage when I was five.
后来再没见过她
Never saw her again.
我学会了恨
I learned how to hate quick.
学会了快速识人 但我却看错你了
I learned how to judge people quicker, and I got you very wrong.
我爸以前总打我和我哥 无缘无故
My daddy used to beat me and my brother just because the sun rose,
莫名其妙 就打一顿
and then whip us just because it set.
这些我都可以忍受
I could take that...
但他打我妈妈的时候...
...but when he would do it to our momma...
你滚开 臭娘们
Get away from me,woman!
你够了 停手吧 听见了吗
That's enough. No more. Do you hear me?
你开枪吧
Pull the damn trigger.
不要啊 快住手
Stop it! Stop!
但你没有杀他吗
But you didn't kill him?
在我心里 我已经杀死他了
In my heart,I did.
所以我向上帝发誓
So that's why I made my promise to God,
我再也不碰枪了
I ain't never going to touch a gun again.
反正我的枪不会给你 你这疯子
Well,I ain't giving you mine, 'cause you're crazy.
该死
Son of a...
该死的
Son of a bitch.
快跑 快撤回这里来
Move,move! Get your asses over here.
快走啊
Let's go!
撤退 快跑
Fall back,fall back! Go!
他们是从地下冒出来的
They're coming from underground.
探照灯 这里是B6 请求立即支援
Searchlight,this is Baker Six. Request immediate support.
目标为YT515
Target is Yoke-Tare-Five-One-Five.
是的 我知道我们在这鬼地方
Yes! Yes,I know that's where the hell we are,
但我估计快挺不住了
but I don't expect to be here much longer!
我请求炮火支援了
I called an artillery strike.
撤退 快点
Fall back. Move. Move!
撤退 有敌人
Fall back! Incoming!
伙计 我在这
Hey,buddy. I'm right here. Right here.
好了
Okay.
掩护我
Cover me.
快走
Go,go!
快走啊 孩子
Get out of here,kid!
过来 孩子
Come here,son.
你知道怎么做 按住了
You know what to do. Keep pressure on it.
不用 我不要血浆 给他吧
No! Don't need plasma. Give it to him.
在那里 我没事 快去吧
Over there. I'll be okay. Go. Go.
格里瑟 带欧文回去
Grease! Get Irv's back.
- 好的 交给我吧 - 一会见
- You got it,okay. - See you soon.
过来 走了
Come on. Come on.
我们得抓紧走了 快点
We gotta move right now. Come on,come on.
快走
Go! Go! Go!
敌军太多 立即撤退
There's too many, get the hell out of here!
快撤
Move! Move!
- 我好害怕 - 这能止痛
- I'm scared. I'm scared. - It's going to help the pain.
不要这样 振作一点
No,don't. Don't you do that. Come on.
史密提 坚持住 我背你走
Come on,Smitty,you stay with me. Let's go. We gotta move.
帮我把他放下来 帮把手
Help me get him down. Help me get him down.
好的
Yeah.
快点 带他走
Come on,let's move. Come on.
伙计 帮不了他了 他已经死了
Can't help him,buddy,he's gone.
- 不 - 走吧 离开这里
- No. - Come on! We gotta get outta here!
快撤
Let's go!
快点 所有人都撤
Come on. Everyone.
撤离钢锯岭
Off the ridge!
你想要我怎么做
What is it you want of me?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我听不见你的声音
I can't hear you.
医务兵 救救我
Medic,help me! Help me!
救救我
Help me!
救我 上帝啊
Help me,Lord.
好吧
All right.
你没事了 放轻松
You're in good hands. Easy does it. Easy.
六...八...
...six... eight...
十四
Fourteen.
赶紧确保他们安全
Get these men secured immediately.
是的 长官
Yes,sir.
- 列兵Ford 有多少人 - 只下来32个 长官
- Private Ford,how many? - Thirty-two only came down,sir.
上帝啊
Good Lord.
- 把伤员装上车 - 遵命 长官
- Let's load 'em up. - Yes,sir.
哈里 我是戴斯蒙
Harry. It's Desmond.
你会没事的 保持呼吸就好
We going to fix you up. You just got to keep breathing. Okay?
- 上校要见你 长官 - 我需要你的吉普车
- Colonel wants to see you,sir. - I need your jeep.
你们在这放哨 盯好日本人
You two stay here,keep watch, keep your eyes peeled for Japs.
- 但是... - 留在这里盯紧了
- No,but... - Stay here! Keep watch.
- 遵命 长官 - 遵命 长官
- Yes,sir. - Yes,sir.
救救我
Help. Help me.
小心 我来了
Watch out. I got you.
手放在这 按住了
Put your hand on it. Keep pressure on it.
- 我会回来的 好吗 - 好
- I'm comin' back. Okay? - Okay.
别急 慢一点
Easy,fellas,easy.
抬下来
Here we go.
抬下来 数三下 一 二 三
Okay,guys,let's go. On the count of three. One,two,three.
求助 医务兵过来
Help,medic over here!
没事了 坚持住 伙计
It's okay,buddy,hold it together.
我们到崖边了 埃里克
We're at the edge,Eric.
坐好了 好吗
You just sit tight,okay?
埃里克 没事的 你会没事的
You're okay,Eric. You're okay,buddy.
该死 这应该没问题
Son of a gun,this is going to work.
一条腿套一个结 埃里克
One for each leg,Eric.
我给你套好绳子 就带你下去
We're going to get you dressed up in a jiffy and get you down.
有我在
I got you.
有我在呢 埃里克
I got you now,Eric.
你要相信我 埃里克
You have to trust me now,Eric. You're gonna have to trust me.
日本鬼子
Japs!
等等 是自己人 快去
Hold on,one of ours. Hold on! Let's go,let's go!
有我在
I got you. I got you. I got you.
有我在的 你会没事的
Come on,I got you. You're okay. You're okay.
汉克 又一个
Hank,another one.
上校 停止炮击钢锯岭
Colonel,call off the artillery attack on Hacksaw.
不能炮击 我军还有一百多人在上面
Couldn't call it in. There's still over 100 men left up there.
让他们停止炮击钢锯岭
Tell them to call off the artillery on Hacksaw.
杰克 坐下 给你拿杯水
Sit down,Jack. I'll get you a drink.
我们失去掩护了
We just lost our cover.
他们来了 我们快撤
They're stirrin', we got to move. Come on.
来得正好 一直有人下来
About time. They just keep coming by the...
- 好的 抬起来 - 来了
- OK,OK. Pick it up. - I got this.
道斯
Doss. Doss.
救救我
Help. Help me.
相信我 深吸口气
You're gonna have to trust me. Take a breath.
我们走 伙计
Let's go,buddy. Let's go.
杰克 你不知道上面的人是死是活
Jack,you don't know if your men up there are dead or alive.
没有支援 不能再上去了
You can't go back up there without reinforcements.
否则就是去送死
You'll end up killing the rest of them.
那就给我援兵
Then give me the reinforcements.
我没有人了 已经没有援军了
I don't have any fresh men,okay? I don't have any troops.
今天有三个营的人都牺牲了
Three battalions got wiped out today.
调配援军至少需要一天
It'll take more than a day to get men in here.
我等不了那么久
I need them faster than that.
没事的
It's okay,it's okay.
别担心
It's all right. It's all right.
没关系的
Everything's okay.
这是吗啡 是好东西
Morphine. It's good.
安静
Shh.
平尼克 我是道斯
Pinnick,Pinnick. Pinnick. It's Doss.
安静 我来帮你
It's Doss. Be quiet. Be quiet. I got you.
- 中弹了吗 - 我看不见了
- Are you hit? - Yeah. I can't see.
安静 小点声
Be quiet. Just be quiet.
不要动 在我在 坚持住
Hold still now. I got you. Hold tight.
好了 睁开眼试试
There you go. Try now. Try now.
我还以为自己瞎了
I thought I was blind!
小点声 能走路吗
Shh... Keep it down. Can you walk?
不知道
I don't know.
我们离开这里 走吧
We got to get out of here,okay? Come on.
很好 接到你了
Good. Okay,we got you.
交给我们吧
We got you.
特德
Hey,Ted.
我是戴斯蒙 我来帮你
It's me,it's Desmond. I'm gonna fix you up.
- 准备好离开这了吗 - 当然
- You ready to get out of here? - Sure am.
主啊 请帮助我再救一人
Please,Lord,help me get one more.
再多救一个人
Help me get one more.
拜托了 帮助我再多救一个
Please,help me get one more.
再多救一个 帮我再救一人
One more. Help me get one more.
再救一人 帮我再救一人
再救一人
One more.
让一让
Coming through.
这些家伙哪来的
Where the hell are these guys coming from?
钢锯岭
From Hacksaw.
- 我以为他们全撤退了 - 没全部撤退
- I thought they pulled out. - Not all of them.
上面有一个疯子 不断送伤员下来
Some nut's up there dragging wounded from the top.
甚至还送下来几个日本佬
Even lowered a couple of Japs.
他们没挺过来 我过一会回来
They didn't make it. Back with you directly.
轻点 准备好了 出发
Easy,easy. All set,move out.
快过来 到处都是日本兵
Get in here. There's Nips everywhere.
见鬼 玉米秆列兵
Son of a bitch. Private Corn Stalk.
你真让人惊讶
You are nothing if not full of surprises.
你要吗啡吗
You want some morphine?
- 当然 或者给我一枪 - 好的
- Hell,yes. That or a bullet. - Okay.
好了
There. There you go.
好了 让我看看
All right,let me see. Let me see.
这里怎么样 还可以
How's this doing? Okay,not bad.
让我看看
Let me see.
没有看上去那么糟
It looks much worse than it is.
女孩们还是会想吻你的
Girls will still want to kiss you.
中士 你先等一会 好吗
Sarge,you okay here for a while?
没问题 快走吧
Yeah,fine. Get out of here.
我会回来的
I'm coming back.
准备好了吗 我们走吧
You ready? Let's go. You and me,come on.
上尉 你一定得来看看
Captain. There's something you gotta see.
一整夜 我们的人不断被运下来
Our guys have been coming down in droves all night.
好莱坞也下来了 我以为再也见不到他了
And Hollywood's here. I never thought I'd see that guy again.
跟我来 他就在这边
Come on,follow me. He's right here.
这究竟是什么情况
What the hell is this?
你还好吗 长官
How you doing,sir?
你好啊 上尉
Hey,Cap.
上尉
Captain.
- 见到你真好 孩子 - 格洛弗上尉
- It's good to see you,kid. - Captain Glover,sir.
你是怎么下来的
How'd you get down,son?
道斯送我下来的 豪威尔还在上面
Doss. Howell's still up there.
豪威尔和道斯做的吗
What,Howell and Doss did this?
主要是道斯
Mostly just Doss.
- 只是道斯吗 - 只是道斯
- Just Doss? - Just Doss.
是啊 胆小鬼道斯
Yeah,Doss,the coward.
- 你就像是狗皮膏药 - 给我
- You're like gum on a shoe,ain't you? - Give me this.
现在练射击 有点晚了吧
It's a bit late for target practice now,don't you think?
- 上来 - 你开玩笑吧
- Jump on it. - You're kidding.
不是 我拖你走
No,I'm going to drag you.
那就来吧
Let's do it.
- 准备好了吗 - 好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
我们走
Let's go.
有追兵
We got company.
快走
Come on.
抬起手臂
Arms up.
你在开玩笑吧 玉米秆
You gotta be kidding me,Corn Stalk.
"你是在打单套结 不是编胸罩"
"You're tying a bowline,boy, not building a bra."
来吧
Come on.
- 准备好了吗 - 好了
- Ready? - Uh-huh.
下去吧
Get on.
- 放我下来 - 是的 中士
- Put me down! - Yes,Sarge.
- 豪威尔中士 - 道斯还在上面
- Sergeant Howell. - Doss is still up there.
- 什么鬼 - 日本人还在追他
- What the hell? - He's got Japs on his tail.
我们接到他了
We got him.
好样的
That's good. That's good.
没事 接到他了
It's okay,we got him.
- 没事了 道斯 - 没事的 道斯
- It's okay,Doss. - Come on,Doss,come on.
你安全了
You're safe.
戴斯蒙 没事了
Desmond,it's all right,it's all right.
戴斯蒙
Desmond.
慢点 振作一些
Easy,easy. Here,come on.
你受伤了吗
Are you wounded?
没有
No. No.
立即将这名战士送至医疗站
Let's get this soldier to a hospital tent,right now.
- 来吧 轻点 - 慢一点
- Come on,easy now. - Easy,easy.
让开一下
Make some space.
我们需要人清理这里
We need someone to come and clean up in here.
欧文在哪
Where's Irv?
- 你说医务兵谢克特吗 - 对的
- Irv? You mean,Schecter the medic? - Yeah.
他没挺过来 休克死亡 血浆不够
He didn't make it. He died of shock. No plasma.
抱歉
Sorry.
我以为只是一个瘦小子 没看清你的本质
All I saw was a skinny kid. I didn't know who you were.
你为国家做出的贡献
You've done more than any other man could have done
远超他人所及
in the service of his country.
我一生中 从未如此看错人
And I have never been more wrong about someone in my life.
希望有一天 你能原谅我
I hope one day you can forgive me.
我们明天要重登钢锯岭
We have to go back up tomorrow.
我知道 明天是你的安息日
I realize that tomorrow is your Sabbath.
这里大多数人 不理解你的信仰
Most of these men don't believe the same way you do.
但他们都知道 你的信仰无比坚定
But they believe so much in how much you believe.
你在钢锯岭的事迹 无疑是一个奇迹
And what you did on that ridge, it's nothing short of a miracle,
他们也想见证奇迹
and they want a piece of it.
有你一起 他们才能攀登上去
And they're not going to go up there without you.
你究竟在等什么 上尉
What the hell is your delay,Captain?
十分钟前 就该发起进攻了
You were supposed to begin that assault 10 minutes ago!
- 我们在等待 长官 - 等什么
- We're waiting,sir. - Waiting for what?
等列兵道斯完成祈祷 长官
For Private Doss to finish praying for us,sir.
列兵道斯为你们祈祷吗
Private Doss is praying for you?
谁是列兵道斯
Who the hell is Private Doss?
我们走吧
Let's go to work.
趴下来
Down. Get down!
趴到地上 快点
Get on the ground. On the ground. Now!
躺下 我有吗啡
Lay down,lay down. I got the morphine.
快点 带他们离开这里
Let's go,let's get these men out of here.
我的圣经
My Bible... My Bible. My Bible...
停下 停下来
Stop. Stop,stop,stop. Stop!
我的圣经
My Bible,my Bible,my Bible.
好的
Okay.
戴斯蒙 你能回家了 我们拿下钢锯岭了
You're going home,Desmond. We've taken Hacksaw.
等一下 戴斯蒙
Hold up,hold up! Desmond!
戴斯蒙
Desmond.
戴斯蒙德·道斯在钢锯岭救回75名伤员
他是第一位获得荣誉勋章的拒服兵役者  这是表彰美国军人战斗精神的最高奖项
戴斯蒙和桃乐茜结婚并相伴终生
尽管做出壮举 他依旧保持谦逊 将一切归功于信仰
我一直在祈祷
I was praying the whole time.
我祈祷着 主啊 请帮助我再救一人吧
I just kept praying, "Lord,please help me get one more."
我救下一人后 继续祈祷 请帮助我再救一人吧
When I got this,I said, "Lord,please help me get one more."
他曾说过 真正的英雄埋葬于此
干预他人的信仰是错的
I would say anyone is wrong
不论对方是谁
to try to compromise somebody's conviction.
无论是军队 还是其他什么
I don't care whether it's army or what it is.
当你有信仰 那就不是玩笑
When you own a conviction, that is not a joke.
那是你的全部
That's what you are.
尽管我对他费尽口舌
Even though I said those things to him
让他带上步枪
in regard to carrying a rifle,
说他不带枪 跟我们就不是一伙人
then he would never be by my damn side at all unless he had a rifle.
直到后来
But then,in the long run,
发现他才是世上最勇敢的一个人
finding out that he was one of the bravest persons alive.
最后还是他救了我的命
And then to have him end up saving my life
这简直太讽刺了
was the irony of the whole thing.
他的脸和眼睛沾满了血
Blood had run down into the fella's face and eyes.
他躺在那 呻吟着呼唤医务兵
He was laying there just groaning and calling for a medic.
我倒出水壶的水 拿出绷带 帮他洗脸
I took water from my canteen, got some bandage,and I washed his face.
我洗净他的眼睛 他立刻睁大眼睛
And when I... was washing his eyes, his eyes came open.
兴奋到不行
Man,he just lit up.
他说 我还以为自己瞎了
He says,"I thought I was blind."
整场战争 我收获的最好回报
And if I hadn't got anything more out of the war
就是他那一刻的笑容
than that smile he gave me, I'd have been well repaid.
戴斯蒙德·道斯于2006年8月过世 享年87岁
-=伊甸园美剧 http://bbs.sfile2012.com=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业途径
-=YTET-伊甸园字幕组=-
翻译: wicky starve 伊茉
校对: 军医大学小迷弟